Genesis 11 verse 1 the Bible says and it
and the whole earth was of one language
and of one speech and it came to pass as
they journeyed from the east that they
found the plain in the land of Shinar
and they dwelt there and they said one
to another go to let us make brick and
burn them throughly and they had brick
for stone and slime had they from order
and they said go to let us build us a
city and a tower whose top may reach
unto where heaven and let us make us a
name lest we be scattered abroad upon
the face of the whole earth and the Lord
came down to see the city and the tower
which the children of men builded and
the Lord said Behold the people is one
and they have all one language and this
they begin to do and now nothing will be
restrained from them that they have
imagined to do go to let us go down and
there confound their language that they
may not understand one another speech so
the Lord scattered them abroad from
thence upon the face of all the earth
and they left off to build the city
therefore is the name of it called Babel
because the Lord did there confound the
language of all the earth and from
thence did the Lord scattered them
abroad upon the face of all the earth we
are all familiar with the story of the
Tower of Babel men coming together and
seeking to build this tower that would
bring them to the very gates of heaven
and the question is asked why why would
men come together and seek to build this
tower and the answer is actually found
in a few chapters back Genesis chapter 6
Venice's chapter 6 beginning with verse
6 you'll remember
that in Genesis six we have the story of
the tower I'm sorry of the flood where
God instructed Noah to build an ark in
essence these men led by Nimrod were
seeking to find a way of escape from a
future flood I want to say that one more
time these men were seeking to find a
way of escape from a future flood they
had seen what happened in the flood they
had or they had known what had happened
in the flood and so they decided we're
going to build a tower that incase God
does this again we will be able to
escape his punishment they were seeking
to build a tower that would bring them
to the very gates of heaven I think
that's pretty daring I mean is the
thought I get is almost as if they were
saying we will come into heaven and
fight against God ourselves pretty
daring for these people to do such a
thing
how many do you think that that was a
pretty daring thing how many of you
think how how crazy of them to seek to
build a tower to reach unto heaven in
Genesis chapter 6 verse 6 we are told
the reason why God brought the flood in
the first place it says there and it
repented the Lord that he had made man
on the earth and it grieved him at his
heart and the Lord said I will destroy
man whom I have created from the face of
the earth both man and beast and
creeping thing in the files of the year
for it repenteth me that I have made
them but Noah found what grace in the
eyes of the Lord these are the
generations of Noah nor was a just man
and perfect in his generations in his
generations and Noah walked with God the
Bible says in no adverse 10 begat three
sons Shem ham and Japheth verse 11 the
earth was also corrupt before God and
the earth was filled with what violence
and God looked upon the earth and behold
it was corrupt for all flesh had
corrupted his way upon the earth and God
said unto Noah the end of all flesh has
come before me for the earth is filled
with what everyone violence through them
and behold I will destroy them with the
earth let me ask you a question
violence what do you think that
represented what was violence how was
the earth filled with violence
wickedness what else murder everyone
doing their own thing
let me ask you a question what does it
take to commit an act of violence there
must be something they again the lie
anger anger remember the New Testament
Jesus said if you hate your brother
without a cause you're guilty of what
murder
so murders an act of violence if if the
world was full of acts of violence in
the days of Noah that means that there
was a lot of something going around a
lot of what a lot of hatred a lot of
anger you can't have an act of violence
without anger without hatred and this is
what was going on in those days the
earth was filled with men hating one
another men doing what everyone hating
one another and so it is very
interesting that these men seek to build
a tower to reach unto heaven why because
they're trying to avoid another flood if
God sends another flood if
this happens again listen carefully if
this happens again this time we'll be
prepared do you catch what I just said
see these men had two options option
number one repent from their wickedness
and there'll be no flood repent from
their wickedness and and God will not
punish us as he did before that's option
number one and obviously option number
two no no no that's the same thing
option number two build a tower how many
of you get the choices before them
option number one repent and there'll be
no need to worry about God punishing
option number two we don't really feel
like repenting we're just gonna build a
tower because we want to continue doing
our own thing and just in case God tries
to punish us again
we're gonna find a way around that
punishment we're gonna find a way around
repentance we're gonna find a way around
doing the will of God so in essence the
building of the tower what was really
defined away around repentance to find a
way that we could actually listen still
get to heaven without doing the will of
God that's what the tower represents it
were they trying to get to heaven were
they trying to get to heaven everyone
yeah what was the purpose of the
building of the tower so that they
couldn't reach the gates of heaven
that's a crazy thought by the way how
are you going to build something that's
going to reach the heaven like sin can
really make you crazy I have a great
idea
we'll build a tower that reaches heaven
yes and everybody brought into it
this tower therefore we might say was a
symbol of men seeking to find a way
around their responsibility to God and
God's responsibility their
responsibility to God was actually check
this out what is God's responsibility to
all of us if we're to sum up one thing
God at the one thing God asked us to do
how would you sum it up love one another
as you love yourself
that's all God asks he said when you
don't we says when you don't do this the
opposite of that is what is hate is
anger and so and so these men decided
you know what now we want to find a way
around love I don't know if you heard me
just now we want to find the way around
the responsibility of actually loving
our neighbor we want to continue to do
the same things that we do we want to
continue to walk in these same ways so
we're gonna try to build a tower that
will be our way into the kingdom of God
so Genesis 6:5 God saw that the
wickedness of man was great in the earth
and that every imagination of the
thoughts of his heart was only evil
continually again verse 11 the earth was
also corrupt before God and the earth
was filled with violence that word
violence it literally means unjust gain
cruelty damage injustice oppression
unrighteousness violence wrong or wrong
doing imagination of men's hearts let me
ask you something how many of you have a
favorite that you like to imagine
when we imagine things it's typically
things that we enjoy is that right I
imagine going you know on a vacation or
I imagine our you know eating this
particular food or I imagine the time
where I will get to you know ABC and
whatever it is imagination is something
that we typically enjoy so Genesis six
is telling us when when the Bible says
of the thoughts of men's hearts were
only evil continually and their
imaginations were only evil continually
it's actually telling us that they were
enjoying have you ever felt good being
angry come on do not look at me like you
feel good come on guys have you ever
felt good being angry being angry at
someone or something you know like I'm
angry leave me alone this is what I want
to be right now what's worthy to say
anger sometimes and this this is wrong
but beloved the human hearts sometimes
enjoys it enjoys reveling in anger and
at this time of the flood the Bible says
this is all mended like it was Justin it
wasn't like okay sometimes I'm angry and
then sometimes you know things are cool
it was just continually that must have
been a pretty bad condition that word
imagination is actually the same word
that is used in Isaiah 26:3
which says that will keep him in perfect
peace whose mind is stayed on thee so so
this lets us know that no mind in those
days were stayed on Christ all Minds all
imagination was evil and wicked
and hatred continually these men were
tower builders my question for us today
is this how many of us are following in
the steps of these men how many of us
today are tower builders finding or
seeking for alternate routes to heaven
who was a guy that led this out
how many of you remember his name Nimrod
you know one you wanna know what the
name nimrod means it means hunter and
another what he was a hunter but the
name actually means rebellion rebellion
and my question for you was this is it
possible that we could be guilty of
building our own towers to try to reach
heaven while at the same time not
wanting to accomplish or not wanting to
do what God has asked us to do what do
you think let me give you a couple
verses first on 4/20 if any man say I
love God and hate of his brother he is a
liar for he that loveth not his brother
whom he has seen how can he love God
whom he has not seen so God says hey you
want to get him to heaven guess what one
of the things you need to do is love
your brother is it possible for us to
try to find ways around doing that do
what I have to I still want to go to
heaven don't get me wrong
how many of us need in here one heaven
raise your hand if you want heaven yes
we want heaven but sometimes we are not
willing to comply with what God says in
order for us to get there so so it isn't
a human nature in human it's in our
human DNA fuel to sometimes try to seek
ways
to shortcuts or to go around what God
demands of us God demands that we love
one another God she's getting on my
nerves
he demands that we love one another but
God you don't understand I don't like
him God demands that we love one another
God demands that we love one another
because the opposite of love is hey so
you can't say well you know I don't love
you I don't hate you but I don't love
you can't do that jesus said he that is
not with me is once is against me he
does not love me
hates me and so God calls us to certain
things first on two three four and
hereby we do know that we know him if we
keep his Commandments he that's safe I
know him and keepeth not his
Commandments is a liar and the truth is
not in him look at how many people in
the world want to get to heaven while
saying is there another way we can do
that without having to keep your
Commandments I mean there's an entire
world out there of people who say yes I
want heaven but don't talk to me about
keeping God's commandments that's
legalism we don't need to keep his
Commandments but I still want heaven
beloved there is no other way
Romans 13:8 says this oh no man anything
but to love one another for he that
loveth another hath fulfilled the law so
when you really want to talk about
keeping the commandments God says it's
sum up in one word which is love so
guess what you might be a seventh-day
adventists and you might be in church on
sabbath and you might say i keep the law
but if you don't have love in your heart
guess what you are not keeping who may
as well be breaking the sabbath
God requires of us love let me rephrase
it this way love is the path to heaven
there is no other way to heaven love is
the path to heaven and the Bible tells
us that God is love
John 14:15 if you love me do what keep
my Commandments the building of the
tower was a was a way in essence for the
people to get around love we want heaven
we just don't want to get there in God's
prescribed way which is to love one
another because we enjoy be enjoy hating
one another
I kid it feels good to the soul
that's the carnal heart speaking that's
the carnal mind speaking so so first
Samuel 15:23 I read it in your hearing
the Bible says for rebellion what was
Nimrod Namie
what does it they mean rebellion the
Bible says here for rebellion is as the
sin of witchcraft and stubbornness as
iniquity and idolatry Wow
witchcraft what is witchcraft it's it's
sorcery right it's sorcery and and when
you know in in in that world when
someone tries to cast a spell on you or
sorcery they're trying to possess your
your mind you become possessed and
witchcraft what the Bible is saying here
is that when we are rebelling against
God it's as if we are possess and Satan
wants to possess us guys you don't have
to be foaming from the mouth to be
possessed by the way all of us should be
possessed oh let me say this all of us
are possessed
let me scare you a little bit more
you're either possessed by the Spirit of
God or you're possessed by the spirit of
the enemy you belong to someone one way
or the other amen
so beloved I want to be possessed by God
I want to be possessed by the Spirit of
God I want to be owned by God the Book
of Isaiah chapter 14 tells us of someone
else who wanted heaven and and this
someone else to a large degree wants
heaven unfortunately sometimes more than
you and I want heaven his name was
Lucifer and remember what the Bible said
about him I will I will what I will
ascend into the heights of the clouds I
will be like the Most High Lucifer
wanted the highest position and place in
heaven he wanted to ascend just like
Nimrod just like these men that built
the tower he wanted a way to the throne
he wanted a way to the throne that did
not require the character of God this
attitude this disposition it exists
today in our minds and in our hearts
because whenever we seek to find a way
to save ourselves outside the Word of
God we are doing exactly what these men
did at the Tower of Babel and in fact
Jesus tells us in John chapter 10 verse
1 he says verily I say unto you he that
entereth not by the door into the
sheepfold but climbeth up some other way
the same is a thief and a robber did you
catch what I just said these men tried
to ascend into heaven by their own
devised method jesus says anyone who
seeks to do that to enter into the
sheepfold which is in one sense the
Church of God but in another sense it's
heaven itself you try to get into heaven
some other way it says you're a thief
and a robber
so here's a question what did God do to
their tower what did he do to their
tower he what here let me read it to you
Genesis chapter 11 verse 6 and God and
the Lord God said Behold the people is
one and they have all one language and
this they begin to do and nothing will
be restrained from them which they have
imagined to do go - let us let us want
let us what everyone let us go down and
confound their language that they may
not understand one another's speech so
the Lord scattered them from abroad from
thence upon the face of all the earth
and they left off to build a city this
is good news guys God came down and
stopped their project whether they liked
it or not and he did it for their own
good but I would listen to me some of us
are building towers I might say many of
us all of us have built towers at one
time or another and God God sees your
tower building he sees that sometimes we
deceive ourselves thinking yeah man you
know I'm going to heaven not realizing
that we're actually bypassing the things
God asked us to do and he's in essence
saying you're building a tower trying to
get to heaven and I am going to come
down to you to stop your building
project
amen we need God to come down and stop
our building projects they help us to
realize that we cannot work our way to
heaven we cannot get to heaven outside
of God's will
there is no alternative path to heaven
Jesus God comes down to destroy our
towers to save us from ourselves he came
down to destroy it one of the first
things he did is he confounded their
language so that they could not
understand one another that's good news
guys when God comes down into your life
to destroy your tower he confounds your
communication he confounds your
communication so that when you're trying
to build with others hey this is right
we should do this and god it's like look
you're hanging out with the wrong people
you're in the wrong company he will make
it so that you no longer understand
their language if you catch what I just
said when God comes into your life to
convert you I was building a tower
before I came to the Lord building this
tower and not yet this time I'm gonna be
famous is I'm gonna God comes down and
he confounded the language so that I
couldn't no longer understand what the
world was saying beloved how many of you
have experienced that in your life you
used to love the language of the world
and the things of the world and then God
comes down and he just totally wrecks
what you thought was a good building
look at this what I have built God comes
down wrecks it and all of a sudden now
you can't understand the things that you
used to understand you you can't connect
you can't you know relate with the
people and the crowds you once used to
relate with God comes down and he
destroys our towers because listen guys
if you build it for all of your life you
would not have what it takes to make
anything to get to heaven if you spent
your entire life building a tower that
you thought was high enough to reach
heaven it would never happen
sin makes us crazy there's a parable in
Luke 14 verse 28 Jesus speaking here
says this for which one of you intending
to build a want which one of you
intending to build a tower sitteth not
down first and counted the cost whether
he has sufficient to what to finish it
les happily after he has laid the
foundation and is not able to finish it
that they behold and begin to mock
saying this man began to build but was
not able to finish were they able to
finish the Tower of Babel if they built
for a hundred years where they had
finished a tower of Babel if they built
for a thousand years would they have
finished the Tower of Babel where the
Tower of Babel ever reached heaven but
love you and I need to sit down and
think do I have enough to build a tower
that is able to reach the heaven the
tallest building in the world is 160
stories and it comes nowhere near to
heaven the distance from the earth to
the Sun is 92 point 96 million miles and
it is nowhere close to what is necessary
to reach heaven beloved the bottom line
is you can never reach heaven if you
spent a million years building so Jesus
comes down to this earth to destroy our
towers and John 3:13 puts it this way no
man has ascended up to heaven but he
that came down from heaven even as the
Son of Man which is in heaven just as
God came down to destroy towers beloved
Jesus came down to this earth to destroy
our towers Matthew 1 it says and he
shall bring
for the Sun 9121 he shall bring forth a
son and thou shalt call his name Jesus
for he shall save his people from their
towers he will save his people from
their towers from their sins from their
edifices that they think yeah this is
gonna get me where I want to go this is
going to be the best thing for me Christ
came down to destroy the tower why
because he knows that the carnal mind is
enmity against God for it is not such as
the law of God and this is where we
build our towers price came down to
destroy our towers to destroy the carnal
mind that we often use to seek to try to
find a way around doing what God asks us
to do not only did he destroy come down
to destroy the tower beloved he didn't
just come down to be a destroyer but
actually he came to bridge the gap you
see Jesus said I am the way the truth
and the life no man cometh unto the
father but by me he was saying your
towers can get you to heaven the only
way you can get to heaven is through me
I am the way I am the truth I am the
life he may as well have said I am the I
am
Tower said whenever the title of the
sermon the tower is not really talking
about the Tower of Babel it's talking
about the tower of Jesus Jesus says I am
the way
check the SOB let me read it to you
again for which of you intending to
build a tower sitteth not down first and
counted the cost whether he has
sufficient to what till what everyone
finish it less happily after he has laid
the foundation and is not able to finish
it all that behold it begin to mock him
saying this man began to build and was
not able to finish listen to me before
Jesus came to this earth he knew he was
coming to build a tower by which men
could reach heaven so before he came to
this earth he had to sit down and count
the cost how much is it going to cost me
to build it because men have tried to
build a tower and it's obvious that that
tower cannot get them anywhere near
heaven but I will come down and I am
going to set up a tower I am going to
set up a tower I am going to set up a
tower that will reach from Earth to
heaven if I be lifted up I will draw all
men unto me and when I draw all men unto
me that means all men are being drawn to
heaven beloved that is a tower that
Jesus came to build in fact Pharm 18 -
says the Lord is my rock and my fortress
my deliverer my God my strength in whom
I will trust my buckler and the horn of
my salvation and my high tower Psalm 61
3 for thou has been a shelter for me and
a strong tower from the enemy Psalm 144
verse 2 my god my goodness and my
fortress my high tower and my deliverer
my shield
and he in whom I trust who subdue with
my people under me proverbs 18 verse 10
the name of the Lord is a strong tower
beloved Jesus came down not only to
destroy our towers to destroy our
concepts and our ways of getting to
heaven he came down to destroy those
towers but to but to bridge the gap and
he would do it through love in the Old
Testament what did they use to build
that Tower of Babel stone and slime and
mortar it just sounds disgusting slime
by what was Jesus gonna use to build
this tower love that's what he would use
the tower would cost love very
interesting I was looking at this word
tower as I was putting my study together
yesterday
and I noticed that this word tower is
used in the Old Testament and and in one
place it is a very strange translation
I'm gonna read it to you in fact we can
get it up on the screen
it's found in Nehemiah chapter 8 verses
verse 4 Nehemiah chapter 8 verse 4 and
the Bible says here and Ezra the scribe
stood upon a pulpit of wood which they
had made for the purpose and beside him
stood Makaha and then it goes on to list
a bunch of people on his right hand and
on his left and then verse 5 and Ezra
opened the book in the sight of all the
people for he was above all the people
and when he opened it all the people
stood up and Ezra blessed the people
blessed the Lord the Great God and all
the people answered amen amen
lifting up their hands and they bowed
their heads and worship the Lord with
their faces to the ground
so the word that it's translated as sour
in other places in the book in in in the
Old Testament is here translated as go
back with me to go back to verse 4 I
need to just put this up on the screen
verse 4 and as
the scribe stood upon a pulpit of wood
pulpit of wood
Ezra preached from this pulpit it was a
pulpit of wood it's translated as a
tower it was from that tower that Ezra
stood up above the people and preached
and and showed the law a pulpit of wood
appropriate of wood they are not feeling
bad a pulpit of wood beloved Jesus on
the cross of Calvary
that was his pulpit and the sermon being
preached was love for God so loved the
world that He gave His only begotten Son
that is why John 3:16 that is why Christ
on the cross is the greatest sermon ever
preached and so what did they do as
Christ was building this what did they
try to do they try to mock him man you
can't finish this you can't finish this
you can't finish this there is no way
that this will ever be finished because
you don't have enough to love people who
are hating you who are spitting on you
who are mocking you who are saying all
these things and doing all these things
against you you don't have enough that
is why I beloved those words that Christ
cried out on the cross it is finished
but a demonstration that love will
always find its way around hate the
tower of love will always find its way
around all the combined force of the
enemy and Jesus says that's what I want
you to have I am the way the truth and
the life this is my pulpit it is the
pulpit of the cross and I want you to
know that this cross was low enough that
every man could reach it I don't know if
anybody's afraid of heights if I was
around in the days of tower Babel you
know people like let's go up a tree like
the cross beloved is not a very high
thing it's no in the reach of every man
woman and child and yet this cross not
more than maybe 10 12 feet this cross is
so powerful that it extends all the way
to heaven that is the bridge that is the
tower that God calls us to build it is
God's love that spans the infinite gap
between heaven and earth and when he
cried out on the cross it is finished he
was demonstrating that love is greater
than hate mercy is greater than anger
eveness is greater than your hatred or
anything else
God says look at what you put my son
through and he still loved you I have a
few more thoughts I'm going to share
very quickly and then we're gonna close
up you remember when
Jacob was running for his life a Bible
said he laid down to sleep and he put
his head on a pillow a rock and he had a
dream remember what the dream was he saw
a ladder and he saw angels descending up
and down that ladder that ladder was a
symbol of the work of Jesus Christ and
his work was best demonstrated at the
cross
in other words beloved the cross is the
ladder whereby you and I may ascend into
heaven I want to say it this way God is
love and love came down love came down
in order that we might find the right
way up and so the only way up is love
beloved if I hold bitterness and
animosity and hatred in my heart for
anyone and yet I still want to go to
heaven I am building a tower and that
tower is not going to get me anywhere
the book of Revelation closes with this
story and it's a powerful one it's in
Revelation chapter 20 verse 9 where the
Bible says at the end of time that the
wicked go up on the breadth of the earth
to try to capture New Jerusalem and I
want you to understand but ever because
I used to think that that these wicked
people represented those who were just
like you know you're thinking like
Napoleon or you know or Hitler or these
people who just are you know totally may
have turned against God and were rulers
against God or whoever you fill in the
blank I'm not judging any of these
people because we really don't know
where they're gonna end up Amen we don't
know who repented at the end of their
lives but I'm just saying we usually
have this picture of people in this
final army again
God who were just like super wicked
really cruel but beloved listen to me in
that group of people will be those who
always wanted heaven those who genuinely
were concerned with their salvation but
but they allowed bitterness anger hatred
unforgiveness while in their hearts they
said I'm gonna hold on to this and I
will find some other way to heaven I am
NOT going to do what God has asked me to
do but I don't want to be in that class
I don't want to be in that group I don't
think there's anyone in here that wants
to be in that group let us look at what
Jesus did for us let us remember that we
were in that crowd it was our sins that
crucified him fact that he still loves
us today it's absolutely amazing
Becky I'm going to ask for you to sing
the Dove came down
[Music]
innocence lost innocence stolen a life
cut you sure a family broken where is
the love where is the gun
does it exist
because love came down to bring
restoration left came down breaking the
shame love came down grace freely given
death for one man left for all left came
down down down love came down down
love came down down down love came down
down
an angel claimed said love was not love
[Music]
pride in his heart an age-old problem
questioning guy
a battle begin babe I that angel
deceiving those who would believe appear
to be light appear to love light but
didn't have love cuz love came down
supreme restoration
love came down breaking the shame love
came down grace really given death for
one man left for all love came down down
down love came
yeah
Oh
good loves or the world he gave up his
son for you and for me dying it is he
didn't his life he did it for love
because he is cuz love came down to
bring restoration love came down
breaking the shame love came down grace
freely given death for one
laughs for all love came down down down
love came down down love came down down
[Music]
love came down
father
thank you Lord that love came down to
show
thank you for providing a ladder for us
that will take us from this gates of
heaven
or to help us to do away with the
building blocks of Babylon the blocks of
hate the blocks of anger the blocks of
depression the blocks of discouragement
help us to use the building block that
matters
that is love
thank you lord
[Music]
Jesus name we pray